犯罪心理 第五季 第23集
Criminal Minds Season05 Episode23
洛杉磯和奧蘭治縣
A heat advisory has been issued
已發出高溫預警
For Los Angeles and orange counties.
內陸山谷地區的氣溫甚至高達43度
Temperatures reached 110 in the inland valleys,
高溫致使電力需求不斷增加
Creating increased power demands.
市縣當局宣佈將按照輪流原則
City and county officials have declared shifting blackouts
拉閘停電應對高溫天氣
On a rotating basis.
洛杉磯水電局女發言人Karen Cramer宣佈..
L.A. DWP spokeswoman Karen Cramer announced ???...
要是不能按時恢復供電那該怎麼辦呢
What if it doesn't come back on?
只不過夜12點到3點拉閘停電
It's only going to be off from 12:00 to 3:00.
是啊 他們是這麼說的 萬一他們搞錯了呢
Yeah, that's what they say, but what if they mess it up?
打住吧
Stop.
- 但是 親愛的 - 別瞎琢磨了
But, honey, it's so--  seriously.
熱瘋了
Ohh...it can't get any hotter.
你在幹什麼
What are you doing?
現在有38度呢
It's 102 degrees.
是34度 但是 好吧
92 but...OK.
再說 我們住在二樓
Besides, we're on the second floor.
什麼情況
What was that?
你待在這兒
You stay here.
你看到人了麼
You see anyone?
對不起
I'm sorry.
好吧 安靜一下
All right. Be quiet.
別打開門
Don't open it.
我沒這打算
I'm not going to.
這堥S人啊
Huh. There's no one here.
哦 天啊 天啊
Oh, God. Oh, God.
沒事的 風吹的
Come on, it's the wind.
走吧 沒事的
Come on. Come on.
見鬼
Damn it!
- 呃 真有趣 - 抱歉啦
- Yeah, real funny. - I'm sorry.
或許刮跑了一個垃圾桶
Maybe a garbage can blew over.
也許是負鼠或別的什麼
Maybe a possum or something.
是啊
Yeah.
- 寶貝兒 - 怎麼
Honey. Huh?
你關窗戶了麼
Did you shut the window?
什麼
What?
我的天啊
Oh, my God!
嘿 Strauss想要什麼呢
Hey, what did Strauss want?
她要我們去洛杉磯
She needs us in Los Angeles.
昨晚發生了入室殺人案
Home invasion homicide last night.
警官發現56歲的Gregory Everson
Officers found Gregory Everson, 56,
被毆打 頭部中槍
Beaten, with a gsw to the head.
他的妻子Colleen同樣被毆打
His wife Colleen was equally beaten
並被多次強姦
And raped repeatedly.
- 多次強姦? - 她報案時這麼說的
Repeatedly? That's what she reported.
等等 她倖存下來了?
Wait, she survived this?
他選擇留她一命
He chose to keep her alive.
故意留下證人
An intentional witness.
這一切都指向其為有條理的罪犯
Everything but that points to an organized offender,
經驗豐富的罪犯
An experienced one.
她能夠認出他麼
Was she able to identify him?
她說他是白人 眼神猥瑣 氣味令人作嘔
She said he was white, with mean eyes and repulsive breath.
從堥鴠~都爛到家了
Rotten inside and out.
他在她丈夫眼皮底下強姦了她麼
Did he rape her in front of the husband?
是的
Yeah.
一起入室殺人案不足以讓Strauss
One home invasion rarely warrants Strauss
親自派我們去查
Personally sending us out.
不 還有更多 彈道測試結果與距離
No, there's more. Ballistics match a double homicide
48公里外的洛杉磯市區內發生的 一起雙重謀殺案匹配
Downtown L.A., 48 miles away.
3天前 兩名婦女被強姦後殺害
Where 3 days ago, those 2 women were raped and killed.
但昨晚是在郊區
But last night was in the suburbs.
他們擔心又出現一個暗夜魔王
They're afraid of another night stalker.
Alfred Lord Tennyson(英國詩人)寫道
Alfred Lord Tennyson wrote,
"穿越層層黑暗
"And out of the darkness
"穿越自然萬物 是那雙手
"Came the hands that reached through nature,
"鑄造人類"
Molding men."
這傢伙的手法太熟練了不像是新手
This guy's way too good at this to have just started.
他在不打擾到鄰居的前提下
He pulled off hours of torture and a homicide
用了數小時折磨並殺了人
Without disturbing the neighbors.
洗劫了受害人的住處
And robbed the house.
這可能是習慣使然
That could be a habit.
你覺得他是當盜賊起家的麼
You think he started as a burglar?
如果僅僅是想殺人
If it was just about the killing,
那他沒必要打劫他們
He wouldn't bother robbing them.
等等 他昨晚是怎樣入室的呢
Wait, how did he get in last night?
Everson夫人說聽到大門外有聲音
Mrs. Everson said there was a noise outside their door.
所以他們走出了臥室幾分鐘
They were outside of their room a few minutes,
等他們回來 他已經在臥室堣F
When they came back, he was there.
他轉移了他們的注意力
He distracted them.
因此他可以從他們臥室的窗戶爬進來
So he could climb through their bedroom window.
我要通知Garcia 看看他的犯罪手法
I'll have Garcia, see if that m.O.
有沒有在別的入室案件中出現過
Was used in any other home invasions.
呃 被害者情況各異
Well, victimology's all over the map.
3起謀殺案 他設法殺死了男人 女人
3 murders and he managed to kill men, women,
老人 年輕人 黑人 白人 拉美人
Old, young, black, white, Hispanic.
分佈相當隨機
That's about as random as it gets.
隨機意味著無法預測
Randomness implies a lack of predictability.
我認為這是關鍵
I think that's the point.
他的犯罪對象是各種人群 他想傳達的信息是
All the varying people in his message.
他希望所有人都害怕他
He wants them all to fear him.
哦 他們會的
Oh, and they will.
輿論都聚焦於昨晚的入室殺人案
Press got ahold of last night's home invasion.
JJ和我去警局
JJ and I will set up at the station.
Dave 你和Reid去醫院拜訪Everson夫人
Dave, you and Reid go visit Mrs. Everson at the hospital.
Morgan和Prentiss 洛杉磯警察局的警探
Morgan and Prentiss, the LAPD detectives
正在Everson家等你們呢
Are waiting for you at the everson house.
你聽到了麼
You hear that?
什麼
What?
完全正確
Exactly.
我們做錯了什麼 犯罪現場竟會如此平靜
What's wrong with us that we're at peace at a crime scene?
熱得要命
Hotter than hell.
一定是技術人員切斷了電力供應
Techs must have turned off the a/c.
看到了麼
Huh. See?
哦 好啊 平靜了
Oh, yeah. At peace.
怎麼了 更多熱潮紅麼 夫人
What's the matter, more hot flashes, ma'am?
我很驚訝像你這種牛人不需要冷靜下來
Surprised a hotshot like you doesn't need to cool down.
大人物什麼時候能到呢
When are the big guns coming?
怎麼了
What's wrong?
你害怕他們會搶佔所有的頭版頭條麼
You afraid that they'll get all the front pages now?
嘿 我從來沒有那樣要求過
Hey. I never asked for that.
警探們
Detectives.
外面很多人嘛
Quite a crowd out there.
我是Matt Spicer 他是Adam Kurzbard
Matt Spicer. Adam Kurzbard.
你好 我是Emily Prentiss 這位是Derek Morgan
Hi. Emily Prentiss. This is Derek Morgan.
嘿 謝謝你們飛過來
Hey, thanks for flying out.
呃 你們有什麼發現呢
So, what have you got?
我們忙得不可開交 這傢伙一周之內席捲全市
Got our hands full. Guy's been across the city in a week.
犯案似乎完全隨機
Seems completely random.
你不這樣認為麼
You don't think it is?
我們是紐頓分局搶劫兇殺組的
We're robbery-homicide in Newton division.
頭兩名受害人正處於我們轄區中央
The first 2 vics were right in the middle of it.
唯一一個使我們趕到這堥茠漲]素是
The only thing that brought us all the way out here
- 子彈 - 還有人身攻擊
- Were the bullets. - And the assault.
所有的受害人均被強姦
All the victims were raped.
DNA匹配了?
DNA match?
他處理掉了證據
He covers up.
Everson夫婦拉閘斷電時
The, uh, Eversons were in their bedroom
正在他們的臥室內
Upstairs when the electricity went out.
那麼疑犯首先切斷了電源
So the unsub cut the power.
不是 水電局計劃輪流安排停電
No. They've got rolling blackouts scheduled.
試圖不破壞全市電力供應
Trying to get through this heat wave
平穩度過這一波熱浪
Without the whole city going dark.
那麼這是不是他選擇這堛滬鴞]呢
So, is that why he came out here?
呃 人們都害怕黑暗
Well, people are afraid of the dark.
而他很可能借助夜色捕獲獵物
He probably preyed on that.
好吧 燈光熄滅了  這傢伙就開始在門口製造噪音
Ok, so the lights go out and this guy starts banging on the door.
為什麼要給他們這種危險信號呢 為什麼不直接闖入呢
Why give them the heads-up like that? Why not just break in?
他也許喜歡讓他們的腎上腺素分泌
He probably likes getting their adrenaline going.
這樣讓捕食變得更有趣
Makes for a fun fight.
聽起來他得逞了 妻子真的被嚇壞了
Sounds like he got one. Wife's real shook up.
我不認為她能有很大幫助
I don't think she's gonna be much help.
為什麼要限制她呢
Why is she in restraints?
她試圖自殺
She tried to kill herself.
先後兩次
Twice.
Everson夫人
Mrs. Everson?
我們是FBI
We're with the FBI.
我們知道你上午已經和警方溝通過了
We know you talked to the detectives this morning.
但如果你能回答幾個問題
But if you're up for a few more questions,
將很有幫助
It could help.
他為什麼不殺了我呢
Why didn't he kill me?
這與你無關
It--it wasn't about you.
這個人一心只想權力
This man only thinks about power
和控制
And control.
放過你正好滿足了他
Leaving you behind gives him that.
現在...
Now...
他有沒有當面和你說話呢
Did he ever speak to you directly?
他有沒有和你說話呢
Did he talk to you?
沒有 他真的沒有
No, he really didn't.
- 很抱歉 - 沒關係
I'm sorry. It's OK.
慢慢來
Take your time.
Greg看著我..
Greg looked at me...
以他習慣的方式...
The way he always did. I...
我們之間並不需要語言交流..
We didn't need words. We...
他只是...
He just...
看著我 我們都明白
Looked at me and we would know.
我試著堅強些 但是我 我...
I tried to be strong, but I--I...
閉上了雙眼...
Shut my eyes...
當槍聲響起 ...
When the gun went off, and...
這是Greg看到的最後一幕
That's the last thing Greg saw.
現在每當我閉上雙眼
Now every time I shut my eyes...
我都會看見他
I see him.
還要這樣多久呢
How long will that last?
你先好好休息吧
You rest now.
呃 我們將讓他上11點的新聞
Uh-huh, yeah. We'll have him on the 11:00.
謝謝
Thanks.
嘿 Rossi去哪兒了
Hey. Where's Rossi?
他正在與Hotch和Morgan交流
He's talking with Hotch and Morgan.
令人難以置信的詳細
It's incredibly detailed.
是啊 Matt Spicer警探還有他的拍檔
Yeah. Detective Matt Spicer and his partner are the go-to guys
是洛杉磯警局紐頓分局搶劫兇殺組的靈魂人物
For robbery-homicide, central bureau, Newton division,
洛杉磯最繁忙的人
The busiest in L.A.
Garcia的電話
It's Garcia.
嘿 Garcia JJ也在這
Hey, Garcia, I got JJ here.
讚美上帝啊 洛杉磯
Praise the gods. Los Angeles
入室盜竊案發生率出人意料地低
Has a weirdly low rate of home invasion burglaries.
我發現了西切斯特的一件案子
I snagged a case in Westchester
有一個傢伙暴力撞倒了前門
Where a guy violently knocked down the front door,
踹了狗 搶走了電視
Kicked the dog, and took off with the TV.
踹開前門傳遞了一條信息
Breaking down the front door sends a message.
他試圖恐嚇受害人
He's trying to intimidate the victims.
是啊 雖然這個賊踹了狗聽起來很惡劣
Yeah, and as horrible as this dog-kicking burglar sounds,
但我覺得我們尋找的傢伙更可怕
I think the guy we're looking for is even more horrible.
Garcia 疑犯有過很多次的練習
Garcia, this unsub's had practice, a lot of it.
或許並不在洛杉磯  但他以前肯定幹過類似事件
Maybe not in L.A., but he's definitely done this before.
這並不是他第一次犯案
Word. This is not his first crime party.
我真的在洛杉磯找不到相似案例
I seriously can't find a single case in L.A.
符合這種程度的情緒宣洩
That equals this level of emotional destruction.
我們需要把搜索範圍擴大到整個南加州
We need to expand the search to all of Southern California.
他可能在任何高速公路網輻射範圍內的其他城市
He can be in other cities with a quick ride on the freeways.
- 好的 這就去查 - 謝啦 Garcia
Yeah. Will do. Thanks, Garcia.
11點的晚間新聞會直播這次的案件
We're going live on the 11:00 news.
你覺得他也會看麼
You think he'll be watching?
夜深時分他很可能已經準備再次出手了
It's late. He could already be hunting.
罪犯為何會選擇這個受害者 選擇在這一天犯案 選擇用這樣的犯案手段
Do you ever look at why this victim, why this day,
這類的問題 曾經困惑過你麼
Why this crime?
- 經常的 - 是麼
- Always. - Hmm.
有沒有想過他們可能只是在錯誤的時間
Do you ever think they were just in the wrong place
- 出現在了錯誤的地方? - 有時會
At the wrong time? Sometimes.
但我根本不信碰巧倒霉之類的說法
Well, I don't believe in coincidences.
此話怎講
How come?
別誤會 並不是說
Don't get me wrong. It's not like I talk
我參透了宇宙萬物法則
To the universe or anything.
我只是堅信萬事都有因果
I've just always believed that things happen for a reason.
但這起案件的來由真是讓人摸不到頭腦
It's hard to find the reason for this, though.
意圖不明的犯罪
Utterly meaningless crimes,
沒有明顯的犯案動機
No obvious motivation.
- 只是純粹的邪惡 - 邪惡在科學範疇內是無法定義的
Pure evil. Evil can't be scientifically defined.
這是一種並不真實存在的 虛構的道德概念
It's an illusory moral concept that doesn't exist in nature.
這個詞的起源和含義
Its origins and connotations have been inextricably linked
和宗教與神話緊密相連
To religion and mythology.
沒有任何跡象顯示此次的罪犯 有任何宗教信仰
This offender has shown no signs of any belief.
- 我...我叫Spencer Reid - Matt Spicer
I'm, uh, I'm Spencer Reid. Matt Spicer.
Jennifer Jareau
Jennifer Jareau.
媒體一直等著想採訪你呢
The media's been asking for you.
那是因為這兒也只有我願意搭理他們了
Yeah, well, nobody else around here wants to talk to them.
大概是我還沒嘗到過苦頭吧
I figure it hasn't hurt me yet.
他們說希望能在11點晚間新聞直播採訪你
Uh, they'd like to interview you for the 11:00 news.
- 你現在有空再過一遍相關重點資料麼 - 當然
Can we go over a few points? Absolutely.
好的
right
這兩個人是這周初被害的?
The first 2 victims earlier this week?
住在市中心 約凌晨兩點時遇害
Downtown. Killed about 2 A.M.
我們在日出時分發現屍體的
We found them when the sun came up.
不是午間?
Not at noon?
沒錯 風化科的警員 是早上六點到達犯罪現場的
Right. Vice were over there about 6 A.M.
家堛漕潃蚆曈ㄟ惘b了十二點
Both these clocks are stopped at 12:00.
那時曾經停電過麼
Was there a blackout?
昨晚才開始停電的
They started last night.
就是說是他割斷了屋外的電線
So then he cut their power.
而昨天晚上他則是利用了全城斷電
But he let the city do it last night.
下次輪到這堸措q是在什麼時間?
Where's the next rolling blackout?
若您正開車經過聖費爾南多山谷
If you're driving through the San Fernando valley,
敬請注意--由於需要輪流停電
Beware--the power in Glendale has just gone out,
格蘭岱爾市剛剛斷電
Thanks to the rolling blackouts.
不要走開 稍後還有更多資訊
Stay tuned for further details.
現在我們來看看天氣情況
Now let's take a look at the weather.
炎炎夏日的盡頭似乎仍然遙不可期
Well, the heat is not gonna break anytime soon,
氣溫在37攝氏度高盤不下
With temperatures still hovering at 97 degrees.
希望夜間能降至32攝氏度以下
Look for overnight lows to be about 90.
明天氣溫基本持平
Same situation for tomorrow...
開玩笑吧
Oh, come on.
寶貝兒 我們到家了
Ok, sweetie, we're home.
警方在上午十一點
Officers arrived at the home of Annie Danzi
到達Annie Danzi的家
Just after 11:00 this morning...
此次有一位幼齡兒童倖存
This time a young child was left behind.
洛杉磯警官Matt Spicer 是調查此次案件的負責人
LAPD investigator Matt Spicer is the lead on this case...
...將在今晨晚些時候由FBI的BAU小組開展
...HELD BY THE FBI's BEHAVIORAL ANALYSIS UNIT LATER THIS MORNING.
這些側寫專家於昨晚到達洛杉磯
The profilers arrived in Los Angeles last night.
我們現在正在Annie Danzi的家中為您直播
We're going live now to Annie Danzi's home.
有消息稱 FBI已經到達犯罪現場
We've been told the FBI has just arrived.
Jareau探員 Jareau探員
Agent Jareau. Agent Jareau.
這已經是輪流停電開始後的
This is the second home invasion homicide
第二起入室殺人案件了
That started since the blackouts.
您認為這三起案件之間有關聯麼
Will you confirm that they're connected?
你們計劃如何保障 這些區域內住戶的安全呢
How are you going to keep the residents safe in these areas?
我們正和市政府官員還有洛杉磯警方緊密合作
We're working close with city officials and LAPD
我們將探討決定進一步的保護措施
To determine what steps we need to take to ensure everyone's safety.
他們會決定叫停輪流斷電麼
Will they call off the blackouts?
這次不會
Not at this time.
Annie Danzi
Annie Danzi.
30歲 單身母親
30, single mom.
她孩子當時在家麼
Was her child home?
Spicer正陪著他呢
Spicer's with him now.
斷電時間是昨晚十點到凌晨一點?
So the power was out 10:00 to 1:00?
還是那一套老把戲
All the same tricks.
- 有強行闖入的跡像麼  - 沒有
Forced entry?-No.
去年夏天實行過輪流斷電麼
Were there rolling blackouts last summer?
每年都這樣
Oh, just about every year.
之前出現過類似的犯罪事件麼
Anything like this happen?
炎熱和黑暗交加之時犯罪率總會明顯上升
Well, crime always goes up when it's hot and dark,
但是這麼嚴重的案件
But this?
從未出現過
No way.
在黑暗中出擊已經成為他的簽名了
Hunting in the dark is definitely a part of his signature.
- Garcia - 在
Garcia. Yes, sir.
請你幫忙查一下近幾年夏天輪流停電時期
I need you to check if there were any clusters
有沒有類似的入室犯罪
Of home invasions in previous summers
先查加州 再擴大到全國範圍
During rolling blackouts in California. Look statewide.
他這回留了一條訊息
He left a message this time.
你好呀(THERE漏拼一個E)
[HELLO THER]
萬事都有第一次
A first time for everything.
你覺得他留這話是在歡迎我們麼
You think he's welcoming us?
誰知道呢
Who knows?
至少現在每一個犯罪現場 他都給我們留下更多訊息
At least he's telling us more with each crime scene.
- 沒受過系統教育 - 強迫孩子觀看
Uneducated. Made the kid watch.
施虐個性
Sadistic.
儘管房間堥S有值得偷的財物 仍舊把房間翻得亂七八糟
Trashes the place even though there's not that much to steal.
暴怒
Angry.
選擇在暗夜奡M覓和謀殺受害人
Chooses to hunt and kill in the dark.
不願意被他人看見
Doesn't want to be seen.
為什麼
Why?
也許他對什麼事心感愧疚
Maybe he's ashamed of something.
但他也不用把這些相框放倒啊
Well, he didn't have to knock those over.
他不希望有任何眼睛盯著他看
He doesn't want any eyes on him.
除了那個孩子
Except the kid.
一定要逼他目睹每一件事
Didn't want him to miss a thing.
你手上拿的是什麼呀
What you got there?
是個機器人麼
Is that a robot?
是隻怪物
It's a monster.
怪物啊 它在幹什麼呢
Monster, huh? What's it doing?
是在保護你吧
It's protecting you, right?
他會讓那個男人離我遠遠的
It's gonna make the man stay away.
你有看清那個人的臉麼
Did you happen to get a look at that man?
還是床底下太暗了什麼都看不清?
Or was it too dark under the bed?
他把我關到衣櫥堨h了
He moved me to the closet.
媽媽叫我把眼睛閉上
And my mom told me to close my eyes.
你能給我示範一下你當時怎麼做的麼
Would you mind showing me how you did that?
做得好 孩子 你做得很棒
That's good, kid. That's really, really good.
所以你完全沒看到他的樣子是吧
So you didn't see him at all?
那個男人走了以後你是怎麼做的
Once that man left, what did you do?
你又躲回床底下了麼
Did you get back under the bed?
我不想把媽媽一個人丟在那兒
I didn't want to leave her.
但是你很害怕
But you were scared.
嘿 Carter
Hey, Carter,
你有沒有那種特別酷的背包
Do you, um, do you have like a really cool backpack
你可以放點衣物進去 然後搬去你表哥家住
You could throw some things in to take over to your cousin's house?
我屋奡N有
It's in my room.
你願意陪我去拿麼
Will you come with me?
聽你的
You bet.
嘿
Hey.
那孩子什麼都沒看到我真的很欣慰
Look, I'm really glad the kid didn't see anything,
那樣可能對他有好處
But it could have been helpful.
但當他用手摀住了眼睛
But covering his eyes like that,
就沒法來摀住耳朵了
That means he couldn't cover his ears.
強迫孩子觀看 這是典型的施虐型性格
Forcing a child to witness this is clearly sadistic.
他意圖毀滅孩子心中的純真 並毀滅他的童年
He destroyed the boy's innocence and took away his childhood.
不明嫌犯自己的童年很可能也是這樣的情況
This probably mirrors the unsub's own experience.
難道這麼說就能減輕他的罪責了麼
That's an excuse for what he's doing?
他的罪責無法被寬恕
There's no excuse for what he's doing.
我們並不是在為罪犯辯解
We're not justifying anything.
他的一切所作所為
Everything he says, everything he does
都能成為我們行為分析的依據
Tell us what makes him tick, that's all.
他在犯罪現場留下的訊息拼錯了
The message that he left us was misspelled,
這表明他沒有受過良好的教育
Which says that he was not well-educated.
他為什麼突然興起想要留訊息呢
Why did he leave one now?
原因暫時還不清楚
That we don't know--yet.
他最近都在洛杉磯犯案
Just because his recent attacks are in Los Angeles
不代表他是本地人
Doesn't mean he's from here.
他一定要等黑暗降臨後才能出擊
Killing in the dark is a must for him.
我們認為這也是他選擇洛杉磯的原因
We believe that's why he's come to L.A.
再加上他隨機選擇受害人這一點
That and his willingness to kill random people
我們認定他是一個機會主義者
Tells us that he's an opportunistic offender,
這種類型的殺手是極其難預測的
And these types are incredibly difficult to predict.
眾所周知 為使當地居民對此做好準備
And as you all know, the rolling blackouts have been announced
輪流停電會提前通知
So residents can prepare for the few hours they'll be in darkness.
不幸的是 這也告訴兇手
Unfortunately, that also tells the killer
這些住戶到時會窗戶大開並關閉房屋警報
Whose windows will be open, whose alarms will be disarmed.
黑暗是他的簽名 已經成為了他的習慣
The dark is his signature. It's a habit,
我們會發現這是他的嗜好
and we'll find That he's always killed this way.
因為他是個懦夫
'cause he's a coward.
某種程度上說 沒錯 他也同樣害怕他人親近
To some degree, yes. He also has intimacy issues.
他甚至會把照片背離自己
He even turns photographs away from himself.
這樣的一個人
It's unlikely that a man like this
是不可能有過戀愛關係的
Has been in any kind of relationship.
也很有可能他有缺陷
There's also a good chance that he has some type of shortcoming.
無論是客觀的還是主觀的
Whether real or perceived,
他肯定在某種方面感到羞愧
He's obviously self-conscious about something.
- 比如? - 可能是生理缺陷
Like what? It could be like a physical deformity.
可能對我們來說只是很小的一件事
It might be something really small to us,
對他來說就是一切
But it means everything to him.
每個人都想融入周圍的人群
People just want to fit in.
有任何一處異於常人的地方
Having one thing that sets him apart from the norm
就可能導致其極端的孤立
Could be what led him into the extreme solitude
和強烈的自我矛盾的個性
Of a violent schizoid personality.
他通過剝奪被害人的能力
He takes his victims' power away,
包括機體和精神力量
Literally and figuratively.
在使他們感到弱小中感到極大滿足感
And he feeds off of making them powerless.
去年整個夏天我們都實行輪流斷電
We had rolling blackouts all last summer,
但這個人從未出現過
And this guy wasn't around.
但他現在卻出現了
Well, he is now.
以他的犯罪手段的惡毒程度
And based on the vicious nature of his crimes,
媒體已經將他命名為"暗夜王子"了
The press has named him the prince of darkness.
"王子" 這稱呼會讓他的自尊更加膨脹的
Prince. That'll fuel his ego.
是啊 他會出現在各大新聞中
Yeah. He's gonna be all over the news.
只要能找到他對黑暗依賴心理的原因 我們就能找到他了
Once we unravel his need for darkness, we'll find him.
他要是回來找我怎麼辦?
What if he comes back?
不會的
He won't.
他不會再傷害你了 懂麼
He can't hurt you again, OK?
你怎麼知道 你都不知道他在哪兒
How do you know? You didn't find him.
話是沒錯 但是我們一定會找到他的
You're right. But I will.
她應該識時務一些的
She should have known better.
你在說誰? 你母親麼
Who? Your mom?
她嘗試跟他搏鬥的
She tried to fight him,
但他手埵竟j
But he had a gun.
她為什麼還要傻乎乎地去跟他鬥呢
Why did she do that?
這個嘛
Well,
Carter 她想盡全力保護你啊
She needed to protect you, Carter.
做出這種事的人 是窮兇極惡的
The man who did this, he's very bad, OK?
我一定會將他繩之以法
I'm going to find him.
我保證 好不好?
I promise. Ok?
好吧
All right.
謝謝
Thank you.
是的 Prentiss 有什麼計劃
Yeah, Prentiss. What's the plan?
今晚按計劃還要輪流停電
Rolling blackouts are still scheduled for tonight.
那警方要怎麼巡邏?
How's LAPD gonna patrol it?
以他們接到的電話
With the number of calls they've been getting,
他們已經分散部署了
They're stretched thin already.
那他們得停止這麼做
Well, then they gotta cancel it.
那就是戰爭 要真那麼做
That's the battle. If they do that,
如果電網超載 整座城市都將停電
The whole city could go dark if the power grid gets overwhelmed.
你說的對 那樣不行
Yeah, you're right. That's not gonna work.
潛在受害者會大大增加
LAPD's outnumbered 10,000 to 1.
好的 有事通知我
All right, keep me posted.
有沒有告訴她我們明天
Did you tell her that we're gonna need to talk to Carter
要和Carter再談談?
Again tomorrow?
他什麼也不會記得
He won't remember anything.
我們有心理分析員可以幫他想起來
We have psychological markers, things that could help him out.
你想讓他再經歷一次?
You want to make him relive it?
如果能幫我們抓到兇手 是的
If it will help us catch this guy, yes.
你也看到他了 他感覺無助脆弱
I mean, you saw him. He feels helpless, weak.
他也無能為力
There's nothing he could have done about it,
但他會一直責怪自己
But he's gonna keep blaming himself.
Carter不願表現出來
You know, Carter didn't reveal that much.
你怎麼知道?
How come you know all this?
因為我小時候失去過父母
Because when I was a kid, I lost my parents.
怎麼回事
How?
酒後駕車
Drunk driver.
你當時在車?
And you were in the car?
沒
No.
你似乎深有體會 好像你親眼見過一樣
You seem to have some insight, as if you witnessed it.
也許是因為我在腦海中想像過 無數次當時的場景
Maybe because I pictured it a thousand times.
我父母...
My parents...
他們 呃
They, uh,
他們在往家趕 因為我病了
They were racing home 'cause I was sick.
要知道 如果他們不是那時候上路
You know, if they hadn't left right then,
他們就不會走那個十字路口
They would have missed that intersection,
那堣]不會是紅燈
And there wouldn't have been a red light.
我失去了父親...
I lost my father...
在我9歲時
When I was 9 years old.
他在我面前被槍擊身亡
He was shot and killed right in front of me.
我也無能為力
There was nothing I could do.
所以我選擇這樣看待
So I choose to look at it like this--
我們的生命中都有重要的人
We all have people in our lives.
有些是好人
Some of them are good.
有些是壞人
Some of them are bad.
但是他們塑造了我們
But they shape us, Detective.
所以你才會戴上警徽
That's why you have that badge.
所以我們現在才坐在車
That's why the two of us are sitting in this car right now.
(謀殺案和輪流停電讓警力陷入癱瘓)
[murders and black-outs paralyze city of angels]
洛杉磯縣輪流停電時刻表
[L.A.county rolling blackout schedule]
孩子怎麼樣
How's the boy?
他很安靜
He's quiet.
現在會談還太早吧?
Too soon for an interview?
是的 我也想在這孩子再回想之前
Yeah, I want to find this guy before
抓住那兇手
we have to put the kid through it.
大傢伙兒 Garcia有發現
Guys, Garcia has something.
好了 大家都坐下
Ok, everybody needs to sit down
因為我要顛覆你的世界
'cause I'm about to rock your world
雖然是以我不喜歡的方式
And not in a way I like to do it.
我反覆查過 你說的完全正確
I have scoured and searched and you were totally right.
兇手以前就這麼幹過
This unsub has been doing it forever.
過去的26年他到處都去過
There is nowhere he hasn't been in the last 26 years.
我沒誇張 每個州都去過
Honestly. Every single state.
本土共48個州 在我看來
Well, 48 continental. My point--
他是我見過的 我們所見過的 最變態的禽獸
He is the worst I've ever seen,
怎麼把各個案子和他聯繫起來的?
And we have all seen some things.
你說的一切 他沉浸在黑暗中
How did you connect him?
Everything you said. He's drawn to the dark.
他在停電時出沒
He shows up during a blackout,
他搶劫 殺人 留一個目擊者
He robs, he kills, he leaves a witness.
那為何沒有引起警方注意?
How's he getting away with this?
犯一次案換一個地方
He never hits the same city twice.
除了洛杉磯
Except Los Angeles.
我把所有資料都傳給你了
I'm sending everything your way
快點開始打印吧
And you better load up that printer,
因為似乎他從1984年的夏天
'cause it looks like he started in Southern California
就在南加州開始行兇了
Way back in the summer of 1984.
感謝上帝媒體還不知道這些
Thank God the press hasn't connected this.
那年的夏季奧運會是在洛杉磯舉辦的
The summer Olympics were in Los Angeles that year.
Richard Ramirez也是 (美國著名連環殺手 外號"暗夜魔王")
So was Richard Ramirez.
他就是從那年開始的
That's the year he started.
他沒走 在洛杉磯住了幾年
Well, he never left. Stayed in L.A. For a few years.
好的 我去查
Fine. I'll look into it.
似乎不明嫌犯是從那個夏天
It appears our unsub started that summer
聖地亞哥的一次停電時開始的
During a blackout in San Diego.
之後他去了橘子郡
From there he went to orange county.
最後到了洛杉磯
After that he ended up in Los Angeles
之後一路沿著海岸作案
And then worked his way up the coast.
他為什麼要回來
Why did he come back?
為什麼要現在回來?
And why now?
又是炎熱的一晚
It's gonna be hot again tonight.
最好去車媞恅
You might be better off sleeping in your car
或是直接逃出洛杉磯
Or just getting the hell out of L.A.
黑暗中任何事都有可能發生
Anything to get away from the darkness and what happens in it.
我們要和阿卡迪亞暫時道別了
All right, we're about to lose Arcadia.
該區域將從晚九點停電至午夜
They've got that 9:00 to midnight shift.
查茨沃思將從晚10點停電至凌晨一點
Chatsworth, you're gone from 10:00 to 1:00.
您可以上網查閱完整時刻表
Check us out online for a full list.
我們一直待到午夜或是停電之時
We'll be here until midnight or I guess until the lights go out.
嘿 看啊 現在室外溫度37度
Hey, look at that. It's a cool 99 degrees here
準確說是37.5度
At 99.6.
大約10:15到的這?
Get here about 10:15?
聽著 我想讓你查查這街區
Listen, I want you to check the neighborhood,
看有沒有監控攝像頭
See if there are any surveillance cameras.
- 可能壞掉了 - Kurz
They may not be working-- Kurz.
謝謝
Thanks.
他留信了?
Did he leave a message?
那雜種留了個嬰兒
The son of a bitch left a baby in there.
活的?
Alive?
是的
Yeah.
嬰兒?
A baby?
是的 長官 非常感謝
Yes, sir. Thank you very much.
怎麼了
Hey, what's up?
今晚每家每戶都有電
Everyone will have power tonight.
他們取消停電計劃了?
They called off the blackouts?
鑒於早前發生的事 不可能再實施下去了
After what happened earlier, we can't give them that again.
- 太好了 我去告訴媒體 - 謝謝
Great, I'll tell the press. thanks
我們要說的是26年堛200戶人家
We're talking over 200 houses in 26 years.
他從聖地亞哥開始時 還只是搶劫
When he started in San Diego, it was all about the robberies.
等他到了橘子郡
By the time he got to orange county,
他搶劫並襲擊受害者
He robbed and assaulted his victims.
第一次殺人是在長灘 他留下了一名目擊者
First murder was in long beach and he left a witness.
他這26年一直逍遙法外
He got away with it for 26 years.
他為什麼要回來
Why did he come back?
大家好 有個好消息
Good news, everybody.
來電了
The lights are back on.
這就對了 黑暗王子
That's right. The prince of darkness
不得不熄滅亮光
Is gonna have to take the night off.
停電謀殺案的嫌犯仍未被抓獲
Still no suspects in the blackout murders.
但調查者們相信
But investigators believe
除去公開的調查之外
there's a reason why he's stayed in Los Angeles
他留在洛杉磯是有原因的
Despite the publicized investigation.
謝謝
Thanks.
媒體的報道是有用的
Well, the media coverage actually helped.
鄰居們都很警覺
Neighbors were hypervigilant.
他們一聽到槍聲就報了警
As soon as they heard the gunfire they called the police.
他這次留言了嗎?
Did he leave a message this time?
是在衣櫥堛瑰成
He actually left a baby in the closet.
那一定代表著某種意思
There's got to be some kind of message in that.
他在羞辱我們 他留下的目擊者
He's taunting us. He's leaving behind witnesses
年紀太小 無法提供幫助
That are too little to help.
好吧
Ok.
為什麼是她們?
Why them?
為什麼是現在?
Why now?
他在輪流停電前殺了那兩個女人
He killed these two women before the rolling blackouts.
她們怎麼了?
What is it about them?
他在一片繁榮 明亮的地方殺了她們
He killed them in a busy, well-lit area.
跟其他的不一樣
It was nothing like the others.
紐頓縣的槍擊案發生率很高
It's, uh, shootin' Newton.
那堛漱H經常能聽見槍聲
People hear gunfire down there all the time.
正適合他作案
He probably fit right in.
是在你的轄區
It was in your division.
他總得找地方開始
Hey, he had to start somewhere.
你覺得只是巧合?
So you think it's just a coincidence?
好 先說不是巧合吧
All right, let's say it's not.
那是什麼意思 他想引起我們的注意?
What does that mean, he wanted our attention?
顯然我們已經夠注意他的
Well, he certainly has it.
你確定從來沒辦過這樣的案子?
You're sure you never working anything like this before?
相信我 他讓我印像深刻
Trust me, this guy makes an impression.
26年前 他就開始了犯罪生涯
He started his career 26 years ago.
跟我一樣
Same as me.
你覺得這都是因為我?
You think this is because of me?
所以才死了這麼多人?
That all these people are dead because of that?
你的轄區有2個女人被殺 沒有倖存者
Two women killed in your division, no survivors.
之後是一對夫婦 留下妻子當目擊證人
Then a couple, leaving the wife as a witness.
之後是母親 留下了兒子
Then a mother, leaving the son.
現在是一對父母 只有嬰兒活下來
Now two parents, but a baby survives.
如果這堶惘閉Y種模式 我可是從來沒見過
If there's some kind of pattern, I've never seen it before.
他重回洛杉磯一定有原因
He circled back to L.A. for a reason.
洛杉磯最早的兩起謀殺案的發生地離長灘很近
The first two murders here in L.A. county  were close by. Long beach
一起在洛杉磯的北部 一起在橘子郡
is on the cusp of L.A. and orange counties.
看看這一起
Let's look into that one.
住宅入侵 丈夫被槍殺
Home invasion. A husband was shot.
妻子存活下來
Wife was left alive.
聽著耳熟
Sounds familiar.
下一起呢?
What's the next one?
在長灘犯案之後 他去了聖莫尼卡
After long beach, he went to Santa Monica.
等等
Wait a minute.
Spicer 你那有親戚嗎?
Spicer, do you have family out there?
是的 我在那兒長大
Yeah, that's where I grew up.
入室搶劫 雙重謀殺
Home invasion robbery, double homicide.
Joe和Sylvia Spicer被殺
Joe and Sylvia Spicer were killed.
那是我父母
Those are my parents.
根本說不通啊
It doesn't make any sense.
讓我看看
Let me see that.
他們死於車禍 酒後駕車
They died in a car accident. A drunk driver.
誰告訴你的?
Who told you that?
我爺爺奶奶
My grandparents.
我記得當時我爺爺叫我起床
I remember my grandfather waking me up.
他們遇害那晚我病了 發高燒
I was sick the night they died. I had a fever.
我怎麼會不記得他們的遭遇?
How would I not remember that happening to them?
也許是你爺爺故意瞞著你 Matt
Maybe your grandparents never told you, Matt.
他們是想保護你
They were trying to protect you.
他們騙我?
They lied?
你是他留下的第一個活口
You were the first child he left alive.
你被廣泛報導
You've been all over the news.
他知道你是誰
This guy knows who you are.
簡直瘋了
This is crazy.
聽著 當Carter說不明嫌犯逼著他
Look, when Carter said that the unsub
從衣櫥堜馴~看
made him watch from the closet,
你退縮了
You flinched.
你不是嗎?
And you didn't?
這傢伙在奚落你
This guy is taunting you.
他留了一個小男孩 現在又留了個嬰兒
He left a young boy alive and now a baby.
他想讓你知道是他
He wants you to know it's him.
我怎麼會不知道呢?
How could I not know?
你知道的 埋得很深
You did. Deep down.
但你小時候受過巨大的心理創傷
But you went through a major trauma as a kid.
你信奉了另外一個故事 因為那個讓你好受些
You believed the story because it was easier.
那現在呢?
And now what?
你想讓我想起真正發生了什麼嗎?
You want to make me remember what really happened?
拜託 都是26年前的事了
I mean, come on, it was 26 years ago.
有什麼用嗎?
What good is that gonna do?
完全隨你
It's your call.
這是那種 催眠之類的東西嗎?
Is this, you know, like hypnosis or something?
不 我只是想領你過一遍那晚的事情
No. I'm just gonna try and trigger some memories
試著喚回一些記憶
By walking you through what happened that night.
好吧
All right.
我應該 呃...閉上眼嗎 還是...?
Should I, uh, close my eyes or...
可以 我只是想讓你盡可能放鬆
If you want. I just want you to try and relax.
好的
Ok.
開始了
Here we go.
是七月
It was July.
氣候炎熱
And it was hot.
窗戶開著呢嗎?
Were the windows open?
嗯
Yeah.
還有 呃 有一陣小風
And, uh, there was a breeze.
嗯 很好 繼續
Good. Good. That's really good.
你能聽到什麼?
What do you hear?
呃 什麼都聽不到
Uh, nothing.
你確定嗎?
Are you sure?
嗯 我爺爺把我叫起來
Yeah. Yeah, my grandfather woke me up
和我講發生了意外
And he told me about the accident.
慢點 慢點 和我一起來
Slow down. Slow down. Stay with me.
有一陣小風
There was a breeze.
你聞到什麼了?
What did you smell?
你認真的麼?
Seriously?
你試一下就是了
Just try.
好吧
Ok.
你聞到什麼了?
What did you smell?
我聞到了什麼...嗯...
What did I smell? Um...
我不知道 呃...
I don't know. Uh...
我聞到了海洋
I smelled the ocean.
我媽媽的香水
My mother's perfume.
Spicer 什麼?
Spicer. What?
煙?
Cigarettes?
好奇怪 我聞到了煙味
This is weird. I smell cigarettes.
你爺爺抽煙嗎?
Did your grandfather smoke?
從不抽
Never.
加油 再想想
Come on, think.
是誰?
Who was it?
你好呀
Hello there.
他說 "你好呀"
He said, "Hello there."
這是他留的第一條信息
That was his first message.
他在做什麼?
What's he doing?
他...他拽著我
He's...he's dragging me.
我聽到我妹妹在哭
I hear my baby sister crying.
我聽到我爸爸 他在吼叫
I hear my daddy. He's yelling.
你滾出去! 不許碰我 你個狗雜...
Get out of here! Don't you touch me, you son of a--
他殺了我爸爸
He killed my dad.
求求你別傷害我的孩子
Please don't hurt my babies.
我看不到他的臉
I can't see his face.
殺了我吧
Take me.
太黑了
It's too dark.
她在求他
She's begging him.
求求你別傷害他們
Please don't hurt them.
我...
I can't--
我看不到他...我死活...
I couldn't see, man. I just--
對不起 我做不到
I'm sorry. I couldn't.
沒關係的 嘿
Ok. Hey. sorry
不 這就夠了 對不起
No, that's enough.
你已經做得很好了
You did enough.
很好的
You're good.
好的 完事了嗎?
Ok. We cool?
他幹嘛要這麼做?
Ok, why is he doing this?
他每次都會留一個倖存者  好讓他們永遠都不會忘記
He keeps a survivor so that they'll never forget him,
但至於你 則有更深一層的含義 因為...
But with you, it goes beyond that, because--
因為他認為是他把你變成了這座城市的英雄
He believes he turned you into the city's hero.
如果你的家長沒有被害
If your parents weren't killed,
也許你就不會成為警探
You might not have become a Detective.
是 但他是怎麼知道的呢?
Yeah, but how would he know that?
他又沒留在洛杉磯
It's not like he stayed in L.A.
他跑遍了整個國家
He's been all over the country.
媒體談論過你的過去
The press has talked about your history.
他沒有被包括在內
He's not a part of it.
而他想要得到這個認可
And he wants that recognition.
他想讓所有人都知道他對你做過什麼
He wants everyone to know what he's done to you.
他要怎麼做到呢?
How's he gonna do that?
那是你女兒嗎?
Is that your daughter?
她在哪兒呢?
Where is she?
他和我妹妹在我家
She's with my sister at my house.
Kristin? Ellie?
Ellie?
(Matt Spicer警探 一個護衛英雄的故事)
[DETECTIVE MATT SPICER -a view of the man behind the shield]
隨著水星宮的上升 我們的能量需求也會上升
As the Mercury soars, so do our power needs.
洛杉磯水電局提醒大家電量已經
L.A. DWP is warning that critical power levels
達到危險臨界 請大家盡可能少量
are being reached and asks that you keep your acus
使用電力 好保持整個城市的電力供給
To a minimum so we can keep the lights on in the city.
Ellie不見了 他妹妹也不見了
Ellie's gone. So is his sister.
他們是在去警局的路上嗎?
Are they on their way to the station?
車還在那 而且電力也被切斷了
The car's still here and the power's cut,
所以不明嫌犯肯定已經去過了
So the unsub was definitely here.
你要去哪兒?
Where are you going?
我們得去他妹妹家看看
We're gonna try his sister's place.
這傢伙喜歡隱私權
This guy needs privacy.
他沒有把她們留在那媗我們看
He didn't leave them here for us to find,
也就意味著他把她們帶到了某處
Which means he took them somewhere.
她的地址是哪?
What's her address?
謝媢y街 1720號
1720 Sheridan.
- 好的 我們在那兒見 - 好的
Ok, we'll meet you there. Ok, good.
我都不知道我們能否在那塈鋮鴠L
I don't even know if we're gonna find him there.
- 你知道麼? 我們不會的 - 什麼?
You know what? We won't. What?
他針對的是你 與你妹妹家毫無瓜葛
This is about you. There's no history at your sister's place.
他也許是把她們帶到了你在聖莫尼卡的老家
He probably took them to Santa Monica to your old house.
Reid 我們這埵b堵車 交通燈全壞了
Reid, we're stuck in traffic. The lights are out.
嗯 這堛漱]壞了
Yeah, it's out here, too.
發電機超負荷了 應該是全城範圍的
Working off generators. Pretty sure it's citywide.
Morgan在另外一條線上
That's Morgan on the other line.
我們要去Kristin家和他碰面
We're gonna meet him at Kristin's house.
咱們快去吧
Let's get over there.
八百萬的人口總數
With a population of 8 million people,
手機信號只需要一段時間便會...
It's only a matter of time before the cell phone reception goes--
(電話被掛斷)
[CALL LOST]
Reid? 你...
Reid? Are you--
哦 太好了  (服務不可用)
[service unavailable] Oh, great.
Spicer 咱們真的應該等後援來了再說
Spicer, we really should be waiting for backup.
沒時間了 那邊有個後門 我去看看
We don't have time. There's a door around back. I'll check that.
他在哪兒呢?
Where is he?
殺了我吧 殺了我吧
Take me. Take me.
殺我吧
Take me.
Matt
Matt.
爸爸 救命
Daddy, help.
放下槍
Drop it.
你先 你先
You first. You first.
把槍放下!
Drop the gun!
求求你了 爸爸 聽他的 爸爸 聽他的吧
Please, daddy, listen, daddy. Listen to him.
別讓他傷害我
Don't let him hurt me.
Spicer 別這麼做 他不殺孩子的 你知道的
Spicer, don't do it. He doesn't kill children. You know that.
他不殺孩子的 你知道的
He doesn't kill children. You know that.
你敢冒這個險麼?
You sure about that?
你放下就是了 Matt
Just put it down, Matt.
把槍放下 不然她的小命就難保了
Put the gun down or she dies.
別向他屈服
Don't give in to him, man.
只要你不屈服 他就不會傷害你
He's not gonna hurt you unless you surrender.
別這麼做 別這麼做
Don't do it. Don't do it. drop the gun!
求求你了 爸爸 爸爸 他在掐我
Please. Daddy, daddy, he's squeezing me.
我不...我不能呼吸了...
I can't--I can't breathe. Breathe, breathe.
你把槍放下你就輸了
Put that gun down, you lose.
他會殺了你的
He will kill you.
你看看他啊 他就是個懦夫!
Look at him. He's nothing but a coward!
爸爸 好疼啊...
Daddy, it hurts.
爸爸 爸爸 爸爸...
Daddy, daddy, daddy...
好了 好了!
Ok. Ok!
不! 不! 不 撿起來! 撿起來!!
No! No! No, pick it up! Pick it up!
撿起來!!
Pick it up!
給我跪下
On your knees.
不要! 不要啊!
Don't do it! Don't do it!
乖孩子
That's a good boy.
你好呀
Hello there.
Matt!
你妹妹長大了很漂亮嘛
Your sister grew up real pretty.
上次我見到她的時候 她還是個小不點兒呢
Last time I saw her, she was just an itty-bitty thing.
還是沒你媽漂亮喲
Not as good as your mom, though.
她老扭來扭去的
She squirms too much.
去死吧!
Go to hell.
別這樣兄弟!
Come on, man!
起來!
Get up!
嗯 好
Yeah, OK.
你覺得她們這下會記住我嗎?
Think they'll remember me now?
爸爸
Daddy.
是你把我毀了 你是想聽這個嗎?
You've destroyed me. Is that what you want to hear?
這個嘛
Well, it's...
還不錯咯
Better.
Morgan 答應我她會沒事
Promise me she'll be OK, Morgan.
來啊 答應他嘛
Go ahead, promise him.
答應他!
Do it and promise him!
- 答應我 Morgan - 好吧
Promise me, Morgan. Ok.
好吧!
Ok!
我答應你
I promise.
我愛你 Ellie
I love you, Ellie.
不! 爸爸!
No! Daddy!
不! Spicer! 你個變態!!
No! Spicer! What is wrong with you?!
抓我吧 求你了
Take me, please.
你抓我走吧! 求你了!
Please take me instead! Please!
不! 不!
No! No!
哦天啊 不!
Oh, God, no!
不! 不!
No! No!
別...
Don't--
一般來講我不是很喜歡小孩子
I don't usually take much to kids.
但是這個嘛...
This one's...just...
很特殊
Special.
我們會找到你的 你個狗娘養的雜種
We will find you, you sick son of a bitch.
喲 這是另一個承諾麼?
Is that another promise?
求求你! 求求你 救命!
Please! Please, help!
Ellie! 哦天啊 Ellie 不!
Ellie! Oh, my God, Ellie, no!
我會找到你的!
I will find you!
犯罪心理 第五季 第23集
== 本季結束 ==
Criminal Minds Season05 Episode23